<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>deep learning on looking at numbers</title>
    <link>http://khalido.com/tags/deep-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in deep learning on looking at numbers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://khalido.com/tags/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>deeplearning.ai: Structuring Machine Learning Projects</title>
      <link>http://khalido.com/posts/deeplearning-ai-part-3-of-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khalido.com/posts/deeplearning-ai-part-3-of-5/</guid>
      <description>This course covers how to think about and improve machine learning systems.
 You will learn how to build a successful machine learning project. If you aspire to be a technical leader in AI, and know how to set direction for your team&amp;rsquo;s work, this course will show you how.
 Course Resources
 Course home Discussion forum
 Week 1: ML Strategy
 Orthogonalization Setting up your goal  Single number evaluation metric Satisficing and Optimizing metric Train/dev/test distributions Size of the dev and test sets When to change dev/test sets and metrics  Comparing to human-level performance  Why human-level performance?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>deeplearning.ai: Improving Deep Neural Networks</title>
      <link>http://khalido.com/posts/deeplearning-ai-part-2-of-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khalido.com/posts/deeplearning-ai-part-2-of-5/</guid>
      <description>Improving Deep Neural Networks: Hyperparameter tuning, Regularization and Optimization
Course Resources
 Discussion forum YouTube playlist for Course 1 course reviews: 1  Week 1: Practical aspects of Deep Learning Train / Dev / Test sets
 training is a highly iterative process as you test ideas and parameters even highly skilled practicioners find it impossible to predict the best parameters for a problem, so going through split data into train/dev/test sets  training set - the actual dataset used to train the model cross validation or dev set - used to evaluate the model test set - only used once the model is finally trained to get a unbiased estimate of the models performance  depending on the dataset size, use different splits, eg:  100 to 1M ==&amp;gt; 60/20/20 1M to INF ==&amp;gt; 98/1/1 or 99.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>deeplearning.ai: Neural Networks and Deep Learning</title>
      <link>http://khalido.com/posts/deeplearning-ai-part-1-of-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khalido.com/posts/deeplearning-ai-part-1-of-5/</guid>
      <description>It had been a while since I finished Udacity&amp;rsquo;s Deep Learning course, so as a refresher I signed up for Andrew NG&amp;rsquo;s deeplearning.ai course.
These are my notes for the first course in the series: Neural Networks and Deep Learning.
Course Resources
 Discussion forum YouTube playlist for Course 1 course reviews: 1  Week 1: Introduction A basic NN looks at housing price prediction, can use simple regression</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grokking Deep Learning by Andrew Trask</title>
      <link>http://khalido.com/posts/grokking-deep-learning-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 01:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khalido.com/posts/grokking-deep-learning-book/</guid>
      <description>Andrew Trask is an AI superstar, having come up with the idea for Generative Adverserial Networks (GANS) - one of the most exicting new AI techniques today - in a bar.
In this book he comes down to earth and explains neural networks from scratch to mere mortals. The book is still being written, but whats there so far is a really good easy to understand introduction to neural networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Udacity ND101: Deep Learning Nanodegree</title>
      <link>http://khalido.com/posts/udacity-nd101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 01:21:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khalido.com/posts/udacity-nd101/</guid>
      <description>My notes &amp;amp; files for Udacity&amp;rsquo;s Deep Learning intro course.
Before the course starts:  Read Machine learning is fun Watch Andrew NG: Deep Learning in Practice (34 minutes) Go though UD730 deep learning course on Udacity Watch Learn tensorflow 3 hour video http://rodneybrooks.com/patrick-winston-explains-deep-learning/  Python resources The course recommneds knowing basic python from here, but I found the following two resources better:
 A whirlwind tour of Python Python Data Science Handbook  Math resources Need to know multivariable calculus &amp;amp; linear algebra.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>