<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>meetup on looking at numbers</title>
    <link>http://khalido.com/tags/meetup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in meetup on looking at numbers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://khalido.com/tags/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SML 2018-09: Deep Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>http://khalido.com/posts/sml-meetup-2018-09-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khalido.com/posts/sml-meetup-2018-09-04/</guid>
      <description>SML&amp;rsquo;s 2018-09 meetup.
 STEM Careers expo on Thu 6th Sep  the talks:
Kosuke Fujimoto: How can we innovate our workstyle at construction sites with Image Classification?  Kosuke, Takenaka Corporation is one of the top 5 largest construction companies in Japan. Their site supervisors perform site visits, record the progress of ongoing construction as well as assign appropriate resourcing from their workforce by writing up the report every evening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SML 2018-08: Deep Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>http://khalido.com/posts/sml-meetup-2018-08-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khalido.com/posts/sml-meetup-2018-08-08/</guid>
      <description>SML&amp;rsquo;s 2018-08 meetup.
 launching StarAI Deep Reinforcement Learning Course  7 week course to take you from RL near-zero to hero 10-15hrs study a week, meet 6-8pm once a week   the talks:
Alasdair Hamilton: Reinforcement learning  The future of Artificial Intelligence is, at least partly, rooted in Reinforcement Learning. During our presentation, the team from Remi AI will take attendees on a journey through their experiences in Reinforcement Learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSS-2018-07: Michael Allwright and Inna Kolyshkina</title>
      <link>http://khalido.com/posts/dss-meetup-2018-07-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://khalido.com/posts/dss-meetup-2018-07-31/</guid>
      <description>Data Science Sydney&amp;rsquo;s 2018-07 meetup.
 data literacy is important for senior execs who data scientists are workng for - there are courses out there for them  Michael Allwright: &amp;ldquo;DATA FOR BAD OR GOOD? THE MINERVA COLLECTIVE&amp;rdquo;  Michael is Co-Founder and CEO of The Minerva Collective, a not for profit which uses data and data sharing for social good, and runs a data analytics consulting company focussed on using data for good.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>